# SHUBHAM DILIP JAIN

Bengaluru, Karnataka ↑ +91 8277186390 **\** 

Shubhamdjain7@gmail.com ✓

https://github.com/ShubhamJain7



#### **OBJECTIVE**

"If people sat outside and looked at the stars each night, I'll bet they'd live a lot differently. When you look into infinity, you realize there are more important things than what people do all day" Calvin said, in one of my favorite Calvin and Hobbes comics. Not only was the 6-year-old right, but what he said really struck a chord with me. I wish to use my skills as a programmer to develop software application for space research and application. It is my dream to create something that would either accompany humans as we explore our universe or help us understand it better.



#### **EDUCATION**

# **BE (Information Science and Engineering) | Dayananda Sagar College of Engineering** 2016 – CURRENT

- Member of the college Quiz, Debate and Hackathon teams.
- CGPA up to the 7th semester 9.53/10

# High School (ISC) | Vidya Niketan School

2014 - 2016

- Passed with an aggregate of 96% in the Science stream.
- Awarded proficiency in Science, Award for Commitment and responsibility and the Star Pupil award.
   Member of the Student Council and school volleyball team.



#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Intern | Mars Planet

JUNE 2019 - CURRENT

As a remote intern at Mars Planet for almost a year now, I have worked on multiple research and software development projects that involved client-server architecture design and development, optical flow detection with OpenCV, real-time object detection and terrain classification from images. My collaboration with Mars Planet continues and I hope to learn more and apply my skills to more out-of-this-world applications!

## Intern | Dolphin Foundry

JUNE 2018 - AUGUST 2018

During my time at Dolphin Foundry, I worked on a project titled "Sporta.in Prototype". I was responsible for the development of backend server written in Python-Flask and working on the front-end of the website using Angular 6. This experience helped me learn the dynamics of a professional environment, how to work well in a team and how to step up and take responsibility.

### Research Intern | Indian Institute of Science

APRIL 2015 - MAY 2015

As an intern at the electrochemistry laboratory, I worked on and wrote a paper titled "The synthesis and analysis of Gold and Silver nanoparticles". This experience taught me about the methodology to be followed for any research and the persistent efforts that must be put in each day.



#### **SKILLS**

- Adept Programmer in multiple programming languages including Python, Java, C++, R etc.
- Artificial Intelligence and Machine learning with Pytorch, particularly in the field of image processing. Some experience in Natural Language Processing. Good at statistical and graphical analysis of data.
- Android app development using Kotlin, Web
  development using Angular, React, Flask and
  Django, Computer Vision with OpenCV, Database
  design and development and Web Automation and
  crawling.

- Debating good reasoning and persuasive skills.
- Accomplished volleyball and basketball player – work well in teams and am able to lead others.
- Good communication skills in several languages.
- Origamist patient, precise, highly organized and relentless.



#### **ACTIVITIES**

**Origami** is a hobby I have cultivated over the past 9 years. As an Origamist, attention to detail and precision are paramount. Some model may require hundreds of tiny parts and can take as long as months to finish. A certain mental calm and tons of patience are required to create art out of paper.

Although **Programming** is often considered a skill, I also think it is my hobby. I have worked on various projects that intersect with multiple domains such as art, communication, physics, biology etc. I particularly enjoy creating art through programs. I have also completed a nanodegree on "Artificial Intelligence with Python" by Udacity. I have been programming for the past 8+ years and it is something that comes naturally to me. I enjoy the challenge of a problem and coming up with innovative solutions for them.

**Star gazing** is a new hobby and I do it every night! I particularly enjoy observing the moon and the ISS when it passes over. I'm still an amateur astronomer but I hope to improve considerably by the end of this year. I also wish to get into astrophotography. Looking at the night sky fills me with awe and makes me zealous to reach further.

**Trekking** is another activity that I enjoy a lot. The challenge of getting to the top, both figuratively and otherwise, gets my blood pumping. I enjoy spending time in nature and observing the flora and fauna. Trekking has taught me the spirit of pushing further to test your limits and go even further!

In my free time I also do a fair bit of **volunteering**. I have been a part of a women's health drive, an initiative to sponsor stationery for a government school and I sometimes visit old age homes to spend time with the seniors. I have never organized such a volunteering or charity drive myself but I hope to change that soon with a book drive.

Apart from the hobbies and activities mentioned above, I am in the process of getting a patent on a product developed by me and my team and am also working on a project in Machine Learning that I hope to get published as a paper. I am also an avid reader, movie buff and enjoy playing volleyball, basketball and table tennis.